Bryce Wilcox

Objective

To apply my creativity and experience to challenging problems which require timely and effective solutions. I am motivated not only by the challenge but also by the value and applicability of the work: I want to realize ideas which can dramatically improve the world.

Recent Experience

 Evil Geniuses For A Better Tomorrow February 2000 - present Software Engineer

With a small team, designed and implemented *Mojo Nation*, a secure distributed file-sharing system with many innovative features including an integrated micropayment system.

• Signet Assurance Corporation August 1999 - February 2000 Software Engineer

With a small team, implemented a transactional, persistent, secure client-server system for an enterprise data backup service. This system implements business rules, legally binding contracts, and secure multiparty business-to-business transactions in one framework.

Network Associates / PGP, Inc. May 1999 - August 1999
Consulting Software Engineer

Helped debug PGP 6.5 and port it to gcc and to HP-UX.

• **DigiCash, b.v.** January 1996 - January 1998 Software Engineer

Designed and implemented a library offering programmable access to the "eCash" technology.

With a small team, designed and implemented a new generation of the "eCash" product.

Designed and implemented a CGI-based web commerce framework with which participating vendors accepted e-cash payments.

Implemented a server providing pseudonymous access to medical records in compliance with French law for Merck, France.

Green Mountain Geophysics, Inc. January 1994 - January 1996
Software Engineer

Designed and implemented an application for surveying, using a GPS receiver and an overhead photograph or map.

Education

University of Colorado at Boulder May 1999
Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Senior project: in cooperation with Network Associates / PGP, Inc., lead a small team that designed and implemented a complete command-line PGP application using a standard cryptography library from PGP, Inc.

Skills



- Writing code designed to be readable in order to facilitate future maintenance and evolution; Code should be written so that it is correct and secure, and also so that it will likely *remain* correct and secure as others make changes to it.
- Technical and non-technical writing.
- Communication and public speaking.

Bryce Wilcox